<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="first_canticle_placeholder">
*A canticle is sung or said here.*
    </string>
    <string name="versicle_matins">
*V.* Lord, open our lips.  
*R.* And our mouth shall proclaim your praise.  
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:  
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen. Alleluia.
    </string>
    <string name="versicle_matins_lent">
*V.* Lord, open our lips.    
*R.* And our mouth shall proclaim your praise.  
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:  
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.
    </string>
    <string name="psalm_95">
Come, let us sing to the LORD; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;let us shout for joy to the Rock of our salvation.  
Let us come before his presence with thanksgiving \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and raise a loud shout to him with psalms.

For the LORD is a great God, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and a great King above all gods.  
In his hand are the caverns of the earth, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and the heights of the hills are his also.  
The sea is his, for he made it, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and his hands have molded the dry land.

Come, let us bow down, and bend the knee, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and kneel before the LORD our Maker.  
For he is our God,  
and we are the people of his pasture and the sheep of his hand. \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Oh, that today you would hearken to his voice!
    </string>
    <string name="psalm_95_lent">
Come, let us sing to the LORD; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;let us shout for joy to the Rock of our salvation.  
Let us come before his presence with thanksgiving \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and raise a loud shout to him with psalms.

For the LORD is a great God, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and a great King above all gods.  
In his hand are the caverns of the earth, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and the heights of the hills are his also.  
The sea is his, for he made it, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and his hands have molded the dry land.

Come, let us bow down, and bend the knee, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and kneel before the LORD our Maker.  
For he is our God,  
and we are the people of his pasture and the sheep of his hand. \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Oh, that today you would hearken to his voice!

Harden not your hearts,  
as your forebears did in the wilderness, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;at Meribah, and on that day at Massah,  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;when they tempted me.  
They put me to the test, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;though they had seen my works.

Forty years long I detested that generation and said, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;"This people are wayward in their hearts;  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;they do not know my ways."  
So I swore in my wrath, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;"They shall not enter into my rest."
    </string>
    <string name="pascha_nostrum">
Alleluia.  
Christ our Passover has been sacrificed for us; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;therefore let us keep the feast,  
Not with the old leaven, the leaven of malice and evil, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;but with the unleavened bread of sincerity and truth. Alleluia.

Christ being raised from the dead will never die again; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;death no longer has dominion over him.  
The death that he died, he died to sin, once for all; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;but the life he lives, he lives to God.  
So also consider yourselves dead to sin, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and alive to God in Jesus Christ our Lord. Alleluia.

Christ has been raised from the dead, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the first fruits of those who have fallen asleep.  
For since by a man came death, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;by a man has come also the resurrection of the dead.  
For as in Adam all die, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;so also in Christ shall all be made alive. Alleluia.
    </string>
    <string name="benedictus">
Blessed be the Lord, the God of Israel; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;he has come to his people and set them free.  
He has raised up for us a mighty savior, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;born of the house of his servant David.  
Through his holy prophets he promised of old,  
that he would save us from our enemies, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;from the hands of all who hate us.  
He promised to show mercy to our fathers \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and to remember his holy covenant.  
This was the oath he swore to our father Abraham, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;to set us free from the hands of our enemies,  
Free to worship him without fear, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;holy and righteous in his sight  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;all the days of our life.   
You, my child, shall be called the prophet of the Most High, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for you will go before the Lord to prepare his way,  
To give his people knowledge of salvation \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;by the forgiveness of their sins.  
In the tender compassion of our God \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the dawn from on high shall break upon us,  
To shine on those who dwell in darkness and the shadow of death, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and to guide our feet into the way of peace.

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen. 
    </string>
    <string name="suffrages_b_matins">
*V.* Save your people, Lord, and bless your inheritance;  
*R.* Govern and uphold them, now and always.  
*V.* Day by day we bless you;  
*R.* We praise your name for ever.  
*V.* Lord, keep us from all sin today;  
*R.* Have mercy upon us, Lord, have mercy.  
*V.* Lord, show us your love and mercy;  
*R.* For we put our trust in you.  
*V.* In you, Lord, is our hope;  
*R.* And we shall never hope in vain.
    </string>
</resources>
