<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="versicle_vespers">
*V.* O God, make speed to save us.  
*R.* O Lord, make haste to help us.  
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:  
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen. Alleluia.
    </string>
    <string name="versicle_vespers_lent">
*V.* O God, make speed to save us.  
*R.* O Lord, make haste to help us.  
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:  
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.
    </string>
    <string name="phos_hilaron">
**Phos Hilaron**

O gracious light,  
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,  
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!

Now as we come to the setting of the sun,  
and our eyes behold the vesper light,  
we sing your praises, O God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.

You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,  
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,  
and to be glorified through all the worlds.
    </string>
    <string name="phos_hilaron_metrical">
**Phos Hilaron**

O gracious Light, Lord Jesus Christ,  
in you the Father's glory shone.  
Immortal, holy, blest is he,  
and blest are you, his holy Son.

Now sunset comes, but light shines forth,  
the lamps are lit to pierce the night.  
Praise Father, Son, and Spirit: God  
who dwells in the eternal light.

Worthy are you of endless praise,  
O Son of God, Life-giving Lord;  
Wherefore you are through all the earth  
and in the highest heav'n adored.
    </string>
    <string name="magnificat">
**Magnificat**

My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,  
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for he has looked with favor on his lowly servant.  
From this day all generations will call me blessed: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the Almighty has done great things for me,  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and holy is his Name.  
He has mercy on those who fear him \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;in every generation.  
He has shown the strength of his arm, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;he has scattered the proud in their conceit.  
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and has lifted up the lowly.  
He has filled the hungry with good things, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and the rich he has sent away empty.  
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for he has remembered his promise of mercy,  
The promise he made to our fathers, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;to Abraham and his children for ever. 

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen. 
    </string>
    <string name="suffrages_b_vespers">
That this evening may be holy, good, and peaceful,  
*R* We entreat you, O Lord.

That your holy angels may lead us in paths of peace and goodwill,  
*R* We entreat you, O Lord.

That we may be pardoned and forgiven for our sins and offenses,  
*R* We entreat you, O Lord.

That there may be peace to your Church and to the whole world,  
*R* We entreat you, O Lord.

That we may depart this life in your faith and fear,  
and not be condemned before the great judgment seat of Christ,  
*R* We entreat you, O Lord.

That we may be bound together by your Holy Spirit in  
the communion of [\_\_\_\_\_\_\__ and] all your saints,  
entrusting one another and all our life to Christ,  
*R* We entreat you, O Lord.
    </string>
</resources>
