<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="phos_hilaron">
O gracious light,  
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,  
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!

Now as we come to the setting of the sun,  
and our eyes behold the vesper light,  
we sing your praises, O God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.

You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,  
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,  
and to be glorified through all the worlds.
    </string>
    <string name="phos_hilaron_metrical">
O gracious Light, Lord Jesus Christ,  
in you the Father's glory shone.  
Immortal, holy, blest is he,  
and blest are you, his holy Son.

Now sunset comes, but light shines forth,  
the lamps are lit to pierce the night.  
Praise Father, Son, and Spirit: God  
who dwells in the eternal light.

Worthy are you of endless praise,  
O Son of God, Life-giving Lord;  
Wherefore you are through all the earth  
and in the highest heav'n adored.
    </string>
    <string name="magnificat">
My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,  
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for he has looked with favor on his lowly servant.  
From this day all generations will call me blessed: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the Almighty has done great things for me,  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and holy is his Name.  
He has mercy on those who fear him \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;in every generation.  
He has shown the strength of his arm, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;he has scattered the proud in their conceit.  
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and has lifted up the lowly.  
He has filled the hungry with good things, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and the rich he has sent away empty.  
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for he has remembered his promise of mercy,  
The promise he made to our fathers, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;to Abraham and his children for ever. 

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen. 
    </string>
    <string name="nunc_dimittis">
Lord, you now have set your servant free \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;to go in peace as you have promised;  
For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;whom you have prepared for all the world to see:  
A Light to enlighten the nations, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and the glory of your people Israel.

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen. 
    </string>
    <string name="spirit">
"Behold, I am coming soon," says the Lord,  
"and bringing my reward with me, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;to give to everyone according to their deeds.  
"I am the Alpha and the Omega, the first and the last, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the beginning and the end."  
Blessed are those who do God's commandments,  
that they may have the right to the tree of life, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and may enter the city through the gates.  
"I, Jesus, have sent my angel to you, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;with this testimony for all the churches.  
"I am the root and the offspring of David, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;I am the bright morning star."  
"Come!" say the Spirit and the Bride; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;"Come!" let each hearer reply!  
Come forward, you who are thirsty, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;let those who desire take the water of life as a gift.  

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.  
    </string>
    <string name="redeemed">
O ruler of the universe, Lord God,  
great deeds are they that you have done, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;surpassing human understanding.  
Your ways are ways of righteousness and truth, \*  
O King of all the ages.  

Who can fail to do you homage, Lord,  
and sing the praises of your Name? \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for you only are the Holy One.  
All nations will draw near and fall down before you, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;because your just and holy works have been revealed.  

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.  
    </string>
    <string name="lamb">
Splendor and honor and kingly power \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;are yours by right, O Lord our God,  
For you created everything that is, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and by your will they were created and have their being;  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;And yours by right, O Lamb that was slain, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for with your blood you have redeemed for God,  
From every family, language, people, and nation, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;a kingdom of priests to serve our God.  

And so, to him who sits upon the throne, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and to Christ the Lamb,  
Be worship and praise, dominion and splendor, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for ever and for evermore.  
    </string>
    <string name="adoption">
Blessed are you, the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for you have blessed us in Christ  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places.  
Before the world was made, you chose us to be yours in Christ, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;that we should be holy and blameless before you.  
You destined us for adoption as your children through Jesus Christ, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;according to the good pleasure of your will,  
To the praise of your glorious grace, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;that you have freely given us in the Beloved.  
In you, we have redemption through the blood of Christ,  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the forgiveness of our sins,  
According to the riches of your grace \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;which you have lavished upon us.  
You have made known to us, in all wisdom and insight, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the mystery of your will,  
According to your good pleasure which you set forth in Christ, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as a plan for the fullness of time,  
To gather together all things in Christ, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;things in heaven and things on earth.  

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.  
    </string>
    <string name="faith">
Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;by divine mercy we have a new birth into a living hope;  
Through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;we have an inheritance that is imperishable in heaven.  
The ransom that was paid to free us \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;was not paid in silver or gold,  
But in the precious blood of Christ, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;the Lamb without spot or stain.  
God raised Jesus from the dead and gave him glory \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;so that we might have faith and hope in God.  

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.  
    </string>
    <string name="humility">
Though in the form of God, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Christ Jesus did not cling to equality with God,  
But emptied himself, taking the form of a servant, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and was born in human likeness.  
Being found in human form, he humbled himself \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and became obedient to death, even death on a cross.  
Therefore, God has highly exalted him \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and given him the name above every name,  
That at the name of Jesus, every knee shall bow, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;in heaven and on earth and under the earth,  
And every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;to the glory of God the Father.  

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.  
    </string>
    <string name="heavenly_city">
I saw no temple in the city, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for its temple is the God of surpassing strength and the Lamb.  
And the city has no need of sun or moon to light it, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;for the glory of God shines on it, and its lamp is the Lamb.  
By its light the nations shall walk, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and the rulers of the world lay their honor and glory there.  
Its gates shall never be shut by day, nor shall there be any night; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;into it they will bring the honor and glory of nations.  
I saw the clean river of the water of life, bright as crystal, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;flowing from the throne of God and of the Lamb.  
The tree of life spanned the river, giving fruit every month, \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;and the leaves of the tree were for the healing of nations.  
All curses cease where the throne of God and the Lamb stands,  
and all servants give worship there; \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;there they will see God's face, whose Name shall be on their foreheads.  

Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: \*  
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.  
    </string>
    <string name="wedding_feast">
Alleluia. Alleluia.  
Salvation and glory and power to our God,  
for his judgements are true and just.  
Alleluia. Alleluia.

Alleluia. Alleluia.  
Praise our God, all you his servants,  
all you who fear him, small and great.  
Alleluia. Alleluia.

Alleluia. Alleluia.  
For the Lord our God the Almighty reigns.  
Let us rejoice and exult and give him the glory.  
Alleluia. Alleluia.

Alleluia. Alleluia.  
For the marriage of the Lamb has come,  
and his bride has made herself ready.  
Alleluia. Alleluia.
    </string>
</resources>